Visual materials from the papers of Clare Boothe Luce.
Prints & Photographs Division, Library of Congress
Visual materials from the papers of Clare Boothe Luce. ca. 1860-1981 bulk 1935-1966
Guide Record
3,740 items (chiefly photographic prints)
Prints & Photographs Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection includes photographs relating to Luce's varied careers (journalist, dramatist, editor, and politician) and her personal life.
For information about Prints and Photographs Division collections and services, see the Prints & Photographs Division's Reading Room Home Page.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Booth family.; Luce family.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987, collector.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.
Subjects
Ambassadors--American--Italy--1950-1960.; Theatrical productions--1930-1970.; Women--Employment--1930-1970.; Women--Political activity--1930-1970.
Form/Genre
Group portraits--1860-1970.; Photographic prints--1860-1970.; Portrait photographs--1860-1970.; Posters--1930-1960.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transfer; Manuscript Division (Papers of Clare Boothe Luce); 1970, (DLC/PP-1970:281), 1994 (DLC/PP-1994:008).
Additional form available
Digitized images of some items in the collection and their associated identifying information are available through the Prints & Photographs Online Catalog, by searching using the title "Visual materials from the papers of Clare Boothe Luce."
Biographical Note
Journalist, dramatist, magazine editor, U.S. representative from Connecticut, and U.S. ambassador to Italy. Born Ann Clare Boothe; married George Tuttle Brokaw, 1923; divorced, 1929; married Henry Robinson Luce, 1935.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes photographs relating to Luce's varied careers and her personal life. Many document official activities and travels she undertook during her service as U.S. Ambassador to Italy (1953-1956); others document Luce's careers as a photojournalist, congresswoman, actress and playwright; some also show her involvement in Republican party politics. Aspects of Luce's personal life are revealed in images depicting her family; prominent friends and acquaintances; family vacations; portraits of Luce as a child and young adult. The collection also includes some portraits of Henry Luce's family; photographs of the Luce's art collection; posters advertising Luce's plays The Women, Margin for Error, and Kiss the Boys Goodbye.
Organization of the Collection
Photographs are organized into three groups with the call number designation "LOT," (LOT 11236, LOT 13260, and LOT 13261). Posters are assigned to the following filing series: POS-SPAIN and POS-TH. One panoramic photograph is filed in the PAN FOR GEOG filing series. Each format is cataloged separately in the Library's online catalog and linked through the collection title: "Visual materials from the papers of Clare Boothe Luce."
http://lccn.loc.gov/00650002
Contents List
- Clare Boothe Luce as Ambassador to Italy and other personal and family photographs ca. 1893-1956 bulk 1953-1956, LOT 11236; 64 albums (ca. 2,106 items); 36 x 59 cm. or smaller (albums).
  Albums are organized by subject into three categories reflecting Luce's career and personal life: Luce as U.S. Ambassador to Italy (LOT 11236-1); Stage and television productions written by Luce (LOT 11236-2); Personal & family photographs (LOT 11236-3).
  Names
  Luce, Clare Boothe--1903-1987--Kiss the boys good-bye; Luce, Clare Boothe--1903-1987--Margin for error; Luce, Clare Boothe--1903-1987--The women; Luce, Henry Robinson--1898-1971--Family; Luce, Henry Robinson--1898-1971--Journeys--Italy
  Subjects
  Diplomats--1950-1960; Rites & ceremonies--1950-1960; Public speaking--1950-1960; Government officials--1950-1960; Boat & ship industry--California--Richmond--1940-1950; Launchings--California--Richmond--1940-1950; Visits of state--American--Italy--1950-1960; Actors--1950-1960; Weddings--1950-1960; Italy--1950-1960
  Genres
  Aerial photographs--1940-1960; Viewbooks--1950-1960; Albums--1860-1960; Clippings--1860-1960
  - Luce as Ambassador to Italy, LOT 11236-1
    Images show Luce on official trips throughout Italy; attending public events and ceremonies; at public speaking engagements; meeting with public officials; posing with government officials and prominent U.S. and other international figures. Includes view books or commemorative albums presented to Luce as keepsakes of visits she made to cities or other places as ambassador. Also includes aerial photographs of Rome, Lake Maggiore, Anzio, and Naples; some images of Henry Luce in Italy.
    - Pacciardi Dinner, April 1953. Events from September through Sicilian trip, December 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 1 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's trip on the Andrea Doria, and her first days in Rome, April 14, 1953, LOT 11236-1, no. 2 (G)
    - 1st official reception, April 29 through the end of August, 1953. Includes visits to Genova, Milano, the NIKI voyage, San Gemignano, etc., LOT 11236-1, no. 3 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's address before the Milano Chamber of Commerce banquet, presided over by its president, Col. James Angleton, May 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 4 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's first official trip to Cassa-Mezzogiorno-Reggio Calabria, May 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 5 (G)
    - Irrigation projects in southern Italy, May 1953, LOT 11236-1, no. 6 (G)
    - Irrigation project in San Giuliano, May 1953, LOT 11236-1, no. 7 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's trip to Matera, May 12, 1953, LOT 11236-1, no. 8 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's trip to Trani, May 12, 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 9 (G)
    - City of Fiesole, July 21, 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 10 (G)
    - Luncheon to commemorate historic "Atlantic Della 2a Crociera", August 8, 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 11 (G)
    - Inauguration of North American College attended by His Holiness, October 1953. Mr. Luce addressing the International University of Social Studies, November 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 12 (G)
    - Mr. Luce visits the Marzotto Estate at Valdagno (Vicenza), November 3, 1953. Souvenir from Sardinia, November 20, 1953. Mr. Luce and Mr. Guzzardi visit Finmeccanica plants in Naples, November 30, 1953. Mr. Luce and Mr. Guzzardi's trip to Milan (includes some souvenirs), February 9, 1954. Mr. Luce's trip to Genoa, March 9, 1954. Souvenir from American Club of Rome, May 13, 1954. Mr. Luce visits "L'Express" in Paris, September 9, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 13 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce attends opening of the Esso Art Exhibit, November 6, 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 14 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's official trip to Sicily, December 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 15 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's official trip to Sicily, December 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 16 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's official trip to Sicily, December 1953., LOT 11236-1, no. 17 (G)
    - Visioni di Alghero (a city), 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 18 (G)
    - Ente Curia Vescovile, Diocesi di Andria (school?), 1954-1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 19 (G)
    - City of Taormina, Sicily, January 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 20 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce sees Eisenhower; American 18th Century Art Exhibit; opening Radar School; visits Gruenthe; television interview; calls on Scelba at Viminale, January through April 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 21 (G)
    - Mr. Luce visits Alfa Romeo factory in Milan, February 9, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 22 (G)
    - Mr. Luce visits Alfa Romeo factory, February 10, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 23 (G)
    - International Automobile Show-Torino, La Fiera di Milano, April 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 24 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's visit to Alfa Romeo stand at auto show in Torino, April 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 25 (G)
    - National War College Reception; Memorial Day Ceremonies; trip to Geneva; Monte Cassini Memorial Ceremonies; De Gasperi funeral; Ambassador Luce returns to Rome; sees associates, May through September 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 26 (G)
    - Naples trip, October 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 27 (G)
    - Personal album of Clare Boothe Luce's life from Maurilio Ottochian, October 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 28 (G)
    - Genoa trip, October 1954; Decoration Ceremony of General Urbani at Villa; Chinese national holiday, 1954; trip to view Salerno flood area, November 6, 1954; Marines Birthday Ball, November 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 29 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce gets degree at University of Trieste, November 1954; receives Junior Ambassadors, July 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 30 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits Sardinia, November 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 31-32 (G)
    - No. III: Ambassador Luce visits Sardinia, November 1954. Also attends Military Attaches' Ball at Palazzo Barberini., LOT 11236-1, no. 33 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at Camp Darby Rivera Service Club in Leghorn, Italy, November 11, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 34 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits Sardegna, November 12-13, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 35 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits Sardegna, November 12-13, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 36 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at various public events, and with associates, November 20, 1954 through February 2, 1955, LOT 11236-1, no. 37 (G)
    - Castellammare di Stabia (a ship), November 21, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 38 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's 2nd trip to Sardinia to distribute CARE packages, and Christening at Naples of Corvette, December 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 39 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce's trip to Trieste, and distributing relief packages in Cagliari, December 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 40 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at Comando Aeronautica Della Sardegna Aeroporto Elmas and Aeroporto di Alghero, December 11, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 41 (G)
    - Teachers & pupils of the English and Ameriphone classes of the Evening Language Schools visit the "Mostra America D'Altri Tempi", December 11, 1954., LOT 11236-1, no. 42 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at various events: N.C.W.C. relief packages distribution, December 22, 1954; departs for U.S., December 28, 1954; reception in Washington, D.C., January 1955; visits SHAPE in Paris, January 1955; returns to Rome, February 5, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 43 (G)
    - Gala opening of "Porgy and Bess" at San Carlo Opera House, Naples, February 15, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 44 (G)
    - Album containing photographs of paintings, statues, and architecture (location unknown), February 19, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 45 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce confers "Medal of Liberty" upon Major Pennacchi, Commander of Italian hospital in Korea, May 1955; attends inauguration of Bologna Center of Johns Hopkins University School, February 22, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 46 (G)
    - Photographs of posters & marchers for I Convegno Gioventu Aclista, March 6, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 47 (G)
    - "American Day" at the 33rd Fiera di Milano, April 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 48 (G)
    - Adlai Stevenson's visit to Rome, April 1955. Sinclair Weekses' visit to Rome, April 1955. Presentation of Credentials to Granchi, May 1955. Sardinian farmers visit Ambassador Luce at Embassy, May 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 49 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits Mostra Internazionale Artiginata at Firenze, May 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 50 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at various events: Naples ceremony for Food Gifts to Italian children; Chinese National Holiday; visits TWA girls; Chamber of Commerce Columbus Day dinner; dedication of Atomic Books Libe; Boston's salute to Rome, October 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 51 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at various events: Dulles' official trip; Mrs. Allen; Stassen's speech; Major Rebecchini's call; Thanksgiving Day; school ball; publicity; Lido plaque award, October 1955 through December 8, 1955., LOT 11236-1, no. 52 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at various events, November 4, 1955 through February 16, 1956., LOT 11236-1, no. 53-54 (G)
    - Aerial photographs taken at various altitudes demonstrating the technical & informational capacities of the various types of aerial photography, October 16, 1956 through November 19, 1956., LOT 11236-1, no. 55 (H)
    - Ambassador Luce visits a church (location unknown) (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 56 (G)
    - Poverty in Mezzogiorno (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 57 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits Cita di Cagliari (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 58 (G)
    - Bari Region photographs (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 59 (G)
    - L'Ente Provinciale Per Il Turismo di Bari (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 60 (G)
    - UNRRA houses in Matera (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 61 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce at social event with Bishop & other associates (no dates)., LOT 11236-1, no. 62 (G)
    - Folklore Friulano Gorizia (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 63 (G)
    - Ambassador Luce visits 12th Air Force, Ramstein Air Base, Germany (no date)., LOT 11236-1, no. 64 (G)
  - Stage and television productions written by Luce, LOT 11236-2
    Includes photographs of actors performing in stage and television productions written by Luce (The Women, Kiss the Boys Goodbye, and Margin for Error); also, portraits of the actors.
    - Kiss the Boys Goodbye (stage production) (no date)., LOT 11236-2, no. 1 (G)
    - Kiss the Boys Goodbye, on the road (stage production) (no date)., LOT 11236-2, no. 2 (G)
    - Margin For Error (stage production) (no date)., LOT 11236-2, no. 3 (G)
    - The Women, a portfolio (cast members portraits), October 4, 1937., LOT 11236-2, no. 4 (G)
    - The Women, NBC-TV "Producer's Showcase" (tv production), February 7, 1955., LOT 11236-2, no. 5 (G)
    - The Women (stage production) (no date)., LOT 11236-2, no. 6 (G)
  - Personal and family photographs, LOT 11236-3
    Includes some portraits of Henry Luce's family, including his father Henry W. Luce and his grandfather Rensselaer William Luce; the wedding of Henry Luce III and Patricia Potter;; a commemorative album documenting construction and launching of the ship S.S. Leonidas, Richmond, Calif.; a scrapbook of newspaper clippings; portraits of Clare Boothe Luce, politicians, and other personal and business acquaintances; the Luce plantation ("Mepkin") in South Carolina.
    - Henry Luce family album, 1893-1935 & many undated photos., LOT 11236-3, no. 1 (G)
    - "This is Where You Came In", (photos of newspaper clippings taken on the date April 3 from 1898 through 1956)., LOT 11236-3, no. 2 (G)
    - Mepkin in Summer, 1939., LOT 11236-3, no. 3 (G)
    - Ann Brokaw & Henry Luce at launching of the S.S. Leonidas Merritt, June 30, 1943., LOT 11236-3, no. 4 (G)
    - Henry Luce at Henry Luce III and Patricia Potter's wedding, June 27, 1947., LOT 11236-3, no. 5 (G)
    - Tale of Politics, a mock play with Clare Boothe Luce and other politicians, compiled by Tere C. Pascone, Christmas 1948., LOT 11236-3, no. 6 (G)
    - Portraits of Clare Boothe Luce & acquaintances (no date)., LOT 11236-3, no. 7 (G)
    - Portraits of Clare Boothe Luce; Clare Boothe Luce at various activities (no date)., LOT 11236-3, no. 8 (G)
- Portraits of Clare Boothe Luce and photographs depicting her personal and professional life ca. 1890-1981 bulk 1935-1964, LOT 13260 (H); 1,338 photographic prints: chiefly gelatin silver, b&w; 33 x 27 cm. or smaller. 6 prints on tissue paper: ink, b&w, 1 color; 48 x48 cm. or smaller.
  Includes portraits of Luce from early childhood through adulthood and portraits of her family; Luce with family members, including first husband George Brokaw, second husband Henry Luce, and daughter Ann Brokaw. Also includes Luce at parties and award ceremonies; socializing with friends, dignitaries, government officials, and associates; participating in political and other professional activities, including speaking at college commencements and at the 1944 GOP convention; working in the Far East and in Egypt as a Life magazine correspondent; touring World War II battle zones as a member of the House Military Affairs Committee, 1944-45; working as U.S. Ambassador to Italy. Also views from family and personal vacations in the United States and overseas; formal large format portraits of Luce; photographs of Luce's art collection; some photos of Luce acting in the play, Candida; portraits of Luce's friends and associates. The LOT also includes six fish prints (artist unknown).
  Organized roughly by subject into 32 folder categories.
  Diplomats--1930-1980; Government officials--1930-1980; Women--social life--1890-1980; War correspondents--American--1940-1950; Private art collections--United States--1890-1980; Events--1890-1980; Families--1890-1980; Rites & ceremonies--1890-1980; Public speaking--1930-1980; Travel--1910-1980; Fish prints--1950-1980
  - Clare Boothe Luce Portraits 1904-1970 (includes color prints), LOT 13260-1 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce, Public Speaking (includes color prints), LOT 13260-2 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce Public Appearances 1942-1948 Carlos Chavez cocktail party, Mar. 29, 1970 Public appearances, 1951-1965 Citadel, Charleston, 1965 Convocation for Peace, Seton Hall Univ., Oct. 17, 1966 (includes color prints) Public appearances, 1966-1981 (includes color prints), LOT 13260-3 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce & Henry Luce 1935-1964. Honeymoon-Cuba 1935-1936, LOT 13260-4 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce with friends & associates, ca. 1930-1974 (includes color prints) Clare Boothe Luce with unidentified friends & associates, ca.1920- 1964, LOT 13260-5 (H)
  - Friends & associates. A-Z, Portraits (includes color prints) Bernard Baruch portaits Unidentified portraits (includes color prints), LOT 13260-6 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce - family, ca. 1890-ca. 1930. Snyder family, ca. 1890-ca. 1938. David Booth, ca. 1904-ca. 1945. Luce family, unidentified (includes color prints), LOT 13260-7 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce - Childhood & school years, Conn.,1911-1919 Castle school, Tarrytown, NY, 1918-1919, LOT 13260-8 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce & George Brokaw (first husband), 1923-1927 (includes wedding photos), LOT 13260-9 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce & Ann Brokaw (daughter), 1929-1943, LOT 13260-10 (H)
  - Henry Luce portraits, 1935-1961, LOT 13260-11 (H)
  - Henry Luce with friends & associates, 1950-1964, LOT 13260-12 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce with godchild Ann Clare Carey, no date., LOT 13260-13 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce - drama career, ca. 1945?, LOT 13260-14 (H)
  - Political conventions and political activity House Military Affairs Committee activities, 1944-1945 House Military Affairs Battlefront tour GOP conventions, 1948-1964 Goldwater campaign, 1964, LOT 13260-15 (H)
  - Journalism career--Vanity Fair Hollywood assignment with Edward Steichen (includes color prints) Far East trip-Chun King, China, 1941 Philippines, 1941 Cairo, Egypt, 1942 Chiang Kai-Shek & Madame Chiang, Gen. Stilwell, 1942 Burma, incl., Maymyo bombing, 1942 (includes color prints), LOT 13260-16 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce - Ambassador to Italy Welcome ceremony, 1953 Various activities, 1953-1956 Turin ceremony, 1955 Villa Taverna, Rome, 1955-1956, LOT 13260-17 (H)
  - Vacations European trip. 1914 European trip, 1920-1921 European trip, 1923 European trip, 1935 Northwind cruise, 1936 Hawaii, 1937 Mepkin Plantation, 1936-1939 European trip, 1938-1939 Spain, Easter, 1952 Caribbean - scuba diving, 1957 Hawaii Sea Life Park, 1970 Italy, 1966-1967 (includes color prints) S.Y. Niki (Yacht), LOT 13260-18 (H)
  - Art Collection (includes color prints), LOT 13260-19 (H)
  - Miscellaneous personal and family photographs (includes color prints), LOT 13260-20 (H)
  - Portraits of Clare Boothe Luce, 1943-1959 (large format prints), LOT 13260-21 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce public speaking, 1946-1959 (large format prints), LOT 13260-22 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce with friends & associates, 1930-1974 (large format prints), LOT 13260-23 (H)
  - Portraits of friends & associates (large format prints), LOT 13260-24 (H)
  - Ann Brokaw portraits (large format prints), LOT 13260-25 (H)
  - Luce family portraits (large format prints), LOT 13260-26 (H)
  - Clare Boothe Luce acting in the play Candida (large format prints), LOT 13260-27 (H)
  - Political conventions & campaigns, 1948-1952 (large format prints), LOT 13260-28 (H)
  - Arrival in Italy as ambassador (large format print), LOT 13260-29 (H)
  - Resignation as ambassador to Brazil (large format prints), LOT 13260-30 (H)
  - Portraits of various friends & associates photographed by Carl Mydans (large format prints), LOT 13260-31 (H)
  - Fish prints (six folders), LOT 13260-32 (H)
- Views of Italy, primarily in the cities of Pesaro, Urbino, and San Marino 1952, LOT 13261 (H); Porcellini, Rug. M., photographer; 135 photographic prints: gelatin silver; 8 x 10 in.
  Photographs show buildings, events, and sites in Fano, Pesaro, San Leo, Urbino, and the city of San Marino. Includes festivals and carnivals; views of the Palazzo Ducale in Urbino; the Pallazo dei Principi; and the convent of Fonte Avellana in Serra Sant' Abbondio. Also views of Furlo Pass.
  Fonte Avellana (Monastery: Serra Sant'Abbondio, Italy)--1950-1960; Palazzo ducale (Urbino, Italy)--1950-1960
  Buildings--Italy--1950-1960; Carnival--Italy--1950-1960; Castles & palaces--Italy--1950-1960; City & town life--Italy--1950-1960; Festivals--Italy--1950-1960; Monasteries--Italy--Serra Sant'Abbondio--1950-1960
  Locations
  Pesaro (Italy: Province)--1950-1960; Urbino (Italy)--1950-1960; Fano (Italy)--1950-1960; San Leo (Italy)--1950-1960
- Posters 1938-1954, 9 posters
  - Leoncio. Feria de Sevilla Granada: 1954, POS-SPAIN.L58, no. 1 (C size)
  - Ruiz Vela. Sevilla Semana Santa, 1954. Granada: 1954., POS-SPAIN.R93, no. 1 (C size)
  - Gilbert Miller & Jack Buchanan present The Women, a play by Clare Boothe with forty characters-- all women., POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 1a (C size)
  - Gilbert Miller & Jack Buchanan present The Women, a play by Clare Boothe with forty characters-- all women. [London]: [ca. 1938], POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 1b (C size)
  - Mendoza. The Women, serial in the Evening Standard. [London]: [ca. 1938]., POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 2 (C size)
  - Play - sensation "The Women" serial begins in tomorrow's Evening Standard. [London]: [ca. 1938]., POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 3 (C size)
  - Jane Marnac presente La piece sans hommes femmes. Paris: Watelet-Arbelot, [1938]., POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 4 (C size)
  - Madame Jane Marnac presente Femmes. [Paris]: [1938]., POS-TH-1938. W87, no. 5 a&b (C size)
  - Hoff. Margin for Error. New York: Allied Printing, [1939], POS-TH-1939. M32, no. 1 (C size)
- Panorama 1954, 1 photographic print: gelatin silver; 6.5 x 30 in.
  - Inaugurazione del primo corso per la preparazione di personale specializzato nell'impiego del radar per La Difesa Antiaerea Nel Quadro Della N.A.T.O.--veduta panoramica della scuola, PAN FOR GEOG - Italy, no. 44 (E size)